vessel.com 2015-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Vessel

Last Updated: March 21, 2015

1\. WHAT IS THIS?

Hello – welcome to Vessel! This privacy policy is simply a statement about how we* collect, use, and share your personal information when you use our Services** or otherwise interact with us. In general, we use data to deliver better, more personalized experiences across our Services. Below we describe how this happens and other uses in greater detail.

This policy only applies to Vessel, and not to third-party websites, applications or services linked from or used in connection with Vessel. You’ll want to read these third parties’ policies to learn what they do with your information.

* When you see “we,” “us” or “our,” we mean Vessel Group, Inc., its subsidiaries and affiliated companies.  
** When you see “Services,” we mean the Vessel website, applications and other online services.

2\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

We collect information about you in a few different ways, including when you provide it to us directly through the Services and from your interaction with our Services. Certain third parties may also collect information about you, either directly or from your interaction with our Services.

Information You Give Us or Authorize Someone Else to Give Us

We collect information that you voluntarily give us. When you sign up to use the Services, you voluntarily give us information like your name, e-mail address, birthdate, and gender, and if you make payments through our Services, you give us credit card or other payment information. If you post content through our Services, like comments and ratings, we may collect that too. We also may supplement information we collect from you with information from third-party sources. Among other things, this helps us better understand you so we can personalize your experience.

We also collect information that you authorize others to give us. For example, we may let you create a Vessel account using your log-in information from a third-party service, like Facebook or Twitter. If you do this, you should check your settings and read that third party’s policies carefully, as you may be authorizing it to share (and authorizing us to collect) information about you like your contacts and people you’re friends with.

Information We Collect Automatically

We collect some information automatically when you interact with our Services, and we may also keep track of your activity across multiple websites. For example, we keep track of your interaction with content and advertisements so we can make content recommendations to you and serve you ads for things we think you’re actually interested in. We also automatically collect technical information, like your internet protocol address, the website you came from to get to ours, and time-stamped logs of data exchanges, like when and how you interact with our Services. Other technical information we automatically collect includes information about the device that you’re using to access our Services, like the type of device, your device ID, and what operating system it’s running.

Information Collected by Third Parties

We’ll sometimes let third parties collect information about you automatically when you interact with our Services, for both their and our benefit. This may include personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online properties and applications.

Here are a few examples of these third parties:

  * Analytics service providers. We work with third party analytics service providers that collect data to help us run and improve our Services. For example, we use analytics software to keep track of usage of our Services, and we work with marketing companies that collect analytics data to improve our marketing across different online properties. These companies may use this data to improve their own services and the services of others, including us.
  * Advertisers and related service providers. It’s important to us that we provide you with a great advertising experience, and we work with advertisers, advertising technology vendors and other advertising-related services to help us do this. These companies typically bring together information about your visits across the websites and applications that they work with, including us, to learn about you and your characteristics and preferences, deliver more relevant advertising to you, track how well ads are working, and provide other advertising customization, auditing, research and reporting. If you want to learn more about the practices of many online ad networks, click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).
  * Applications and services. We may let you connect to third-party applications and services, like payment applications or social networking services. When you interact with these applications and services, these companies may collect their own information about you.
  * Business partners. We may let some of our other business partners, like third parties that provide content on our Services, automatically collect information about you.

We don’t control third parties like the ones listed above, so this policy does not apply to them, and we are not responsible for how these third parties use information about you that they collect. To learn about the information-handling practices of these third parties, we recommend you review their separate and independent privacy policies.

Cookies and Other Technologies

We and the third parties described above use cookies and other technologies to facilitate the automatic collection of your information described above.

  * Cookies. Cookies are small data files stored on your device when you interact with websites and other online channels and applications. Among other things, we and the third parties described above use cookies to operate our Services, improve your experience with our Services and improve your advertising experience on and off our Services.
  * Other Technologies. We may also collect information using web beacons or technologies similar to cookies, like device identifiers, browser storage and plugins. Web beacons are electronic images that often work in conjunction with cookies. We use web beacons and these other technologies on our Services and in our e-mails for similar purposes as cookies, as well as to deliver cookies and understand marketing and e-mail campaign effectiveness.

3\. HOW DO WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?

We use information we collect about you for a few different purposes, either as described in this policy or as we otherwise disclose to you when you interact with our Services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * operate, analyze and improve our internal operations, systems, products, and Services;
  * learn about you and your preferences to enhance and personalize our services and advertising and marketing efforts;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * provide account and service information, like order and payment confirmations, technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative communications;
  * communicate with you for marketing purposes, such as to inform you about products, events, promotions, offers and other news from us and our business partners;
  * communicate with you to help improve our Service;
  * link or combine information about you with information from third-party sources; and
  * protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized or illegal activity.

By using our Services, you’re agreeing to the storage and processing of your personal information in the United States and other countries in which we have facilities that may not have the same data protection laws as your home country.

4\. HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED?

Information You Share

Our Services may allow you to share your actions, comments, content, and information publicly or with other people. For example, we may allow you to post reviews and comments to public forums, or you may connect to, and share information on and using, third-party services. Please be mindful of your own privacy needs as you choose who you connect with and what to share and make public. We can’t control the privacy or security of information you choose to make public or share with others, and this policy does not apply to that information. If you share information about others, we suggest you get their permission first before doing so.

Information We May Share

We do not share your personal information with third parties other than as follows:

  * With your consent, we may share your information with third parties, subject to their separate and independent privacy policies. For example, we may ask for your consent to share your information with one of our business partners in order for you to participate in a joint promotional program with the partner.
  * We use third-party consultants and other service providers who may need access to your information to help us operate and improve our Services. For example, we work with companies who provide services for technology infrastructure, analytics, payment processing, customer service, marketing and communications.
  * We may share your information to (a) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process, (b) protect the rights and property of us, our agents, partners, customers, and others, including to enforce our agreements, policies, and terms of use or (c) detect, prevent or otherwise address illegal or suspected illegal activities, security or technical issues.
  * We may share information with our current or future affiliates, which means other companies controlled by, controlling or under common control with us, in which case we will require those affiliates to honor this policy.
  * We may transfer your information to a third party in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction, or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to third parties.
  * We may share information with our content partners when you visit or interact with their pages through our Services.
  * We may share aggregated or de-identified information with third parties.

Notice to California Residents - Your California Privacy Rights (As Provided by California Civil Code section 1798.83).

A California resident who has given personal information to a business for personal, family, or household purposes (a “California Customer”) may ask if the business has shared personal information with any third parties for their direct marketing use. In general, if a California Customer asks, California law may require that the business give a list of all third parties to whom the business shared information in the prior calendar year and a list of the types of personal information shared. California Customers may ask about how we comply with this law by contacting us [here](https://www.vessel.com/help/contact). Please note that we will respond to one request per California Customer each year. We do not respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address.

5\. HOW CAN YOU KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SECURE?

Your security is very important to us, and we take steps to help protect your personal information. That said, no security measures are completely secure so we can’t guarantee the security of the information you provide to us. To help protect your information, you should not share your Vessel account information or password, reuse your password on other websites, or use a password you have used on other websites. If you share your account information or password with others or allow others to access your Vessel account, you will be responsible for their actions. While you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of your account information, if you become aware of a security issue affecting our Services or any authorized use of your Vessel account, please let us know immediately by contacting us [here](https://www.vessel.com/help/contact).

6\. WHAT CHOICES DO YOU HAVE ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION?

There are a number of ways you can learn about, control and make changes to how we and third parties collect, use and share your information. For example:

  * Profile Information. You may update your profile information through our [Account Settings](https://www.vessel.com/account) page or by sending us requests about your information [here](https://www.vessel.com/help/contact).
  * Communications from us. You may opt out of receiving certain e-mails relating to promotions and marketing from us by following the instructions in those e-mails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional e-mails, such as e-mails about your account or our ongoing business relations. If you do not want us to track e-mails we send you, some e-mail services let you change your display to turn off HTML or disable download of images which should effectively disable our e-mail tracking.
  * Cookies. Many web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from our servers. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features of our Services and can remove opt-out cookies used to express your choice about online tracking and personalized ads. You can choose to opt-out of use of cookies by many of our advertisers, advertising technology vendors and other advertising-related services who help deliver ads tailored to your profile and preferences by clicking [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). If you remove your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choices.
  * Device settings. Devices and device system software provide certain opt-out choices that you can control. For example, Apple iOS and Google Play Services provide an opt-out choice that you can use to control in-app advertisements, and mobile device operating systems provide opt-out choices for push notifications or alerts and collection of location information. Please consult your device settings for more information or to opt out using these mechanisms.
  * Facebook advertising. If you don’t want Facebook to show you ads based on your activity on our websites or apps, visit Facebook to change your opt-out settings [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/).

While we and others give you choices described in this policy, there are many ways web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of or honor every mechanism.

7\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may change this policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above.

8\. QUESTIONS

Thank you so much for your interest in Vessel and for reading this policy. We hope you enjoy our services. If you have any questions about this policy, please contact us [here](https://www.vessel.com/help/contact) or at:

Vessel Group, Inc.  
660 4th Street #417  
San Francisco, CA 94107
